<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alexander Makarov</title>
    <link>https://samdark.github.io/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Alexander Makarov</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 12:39:18 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://samdark.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Yii 2.0 Logging and PSR-3</title>
      <link>https://samdark.github.io/blog/yii-2.0-logging-and-psr-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 12:39:18 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samdark.github.io/blog/yii-2.0-logging-and-psr-3/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;It is 2017 and major parts of PHP community are all about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.php-fig.org/psr/&#34;&gt;PSRs: PHP standard recommendations&lt;/a&gt;
which aim is to make parts of frameworks reusable. There is PSR-3 about logging and quite a number of logging libraries
following it among which &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Seldaek/monolog&#34;&gt;Monolog&lt;/a&gt; is the most widely used one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three questions often asked about Yii 2.0 in this regard:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why Yii 2.0 isn&amp;rsquo;t PSR-3 compatible?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do I use PSR-3 compatible logger in Yii 2.0?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is there a plan to extract a standalone PSR-3 compatible logging library from Yii 2.0?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s answer these.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-yii-2-0-isn-t-psr-3-compatible&#34;&gt;Why Yii 2.0 isn&amp;rsquo;t PSR-3 compatible?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.yiiframework.com/doc-2.0/guide-runtime-logging.html&#34;&gt;Yii 2.0 logger&lt;/a&gt; is one of the well done parts of
the framework. It&amp;rsquo;s stable, easy to extend, performant and really powerful when it comes to features. It was
implemented at early stages of yet secret pre-alpha development of the framework and was not changed much since then.
The design is very close to what was done in Yii 1.0 so we can think of 2008 as the year when logger design formed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The year is important because it&amp;rsquo;s way before PHP-FIG group which is responsible for designing PSRs formed. At the time
Yii 2.0 was in alpha stage we had a proven logger design with worked well with Yii 1.0 and Yii 1.1 and PSR-3 wasn&amp;rsquo;t
a thing yet: there were nothing special about loggers implementing it and there was no benefits for Yii framework
adopting it. So then we decided not to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now it&amp;rsquo;s time to re-decide it for 2.1 since there are certain pros in being PSR-3 compatible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-do-i-use-psr-3-compatible-logger-in-yii-2-0&#34;&gt;How do I use PSR-3 compatible logger in Yii 2.0?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yii&amp;rsquo;s logging facility is quite flexible. There&amp;rsquo;s a central dispatcher component which is collecting log messages and
then flushes them to individual &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.yiiframework.com/doc-2.0/guide-runtime-logging.html#log-targets&#34;&gt;log targets&lt;/a&gt;,
such as file target or email target that actually do the job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yii&amp;rsquo;s log targets are easy to extend but considering the popularity of PSR-3 and especially
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Seldaek/monolog&#34;&gt;Monolog&lt;/a&gt; it is tempting to reuse what&amp;rsquo;s already done. For example, to send logs
to a Slack chat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve put together &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/samdark/yii2-psr-log-target&#34;&gt;an extension&lt;/a&gt; which allows you to use any PSR-3
compatible logger as Yii log target.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is does it translating Yii&amp;rsquo;s log levels to alike PSR-3 log levels and actually forwarding logs to PSR-3 compatible
logger configured. Configuration is fairly easy, you can find it &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/samdark/yii2-psr-log-target&#34;&gt;at extension page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;is-there-a-plan-to-extract-a-standalone-psr-3-compatible-logging-library-from-yii-2-0&#34;&gt;Is there a plan to extract a standalone PSR-3 compatible logging library from Yii 2.0?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yii was never meant to be a set of standalone libraries. Independent components are nice but there is a cost of not
reusing what&amp;rsquo;s available in the framework which in some case may result in bloated code and too abstract solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Logger may be an exception since it&amp;rsquo;s not relying on the framework much, it&amp;rsquo;s framework that relies on it. An attempt
to extract logger may succeed and since we have a good design it may even become close in popularity to Monolog. So
overall it is worth trying and, I think, I&amp;rsquo;ll work on it if &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.patreon.com/samdark&#34;&gt;Patreon campaign&lt;/a&gt;
will bring me enough time for it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Kipple Please</title>
      <link>https://samdark.github.io/blog/no-kipple-please/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 21:52:28 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samdark.github.io/blog/no-kipple-please/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Kipple is useless objects, like junk mail or match folders after you use the last match or gum wrappers or yesterday&amp;rsquo;s
homeopape. When nobody&amp;rsquo;s around, kipple reproduces itself. For instance, if you go to bed leaving any kipple around
your apartment, when you wake up the next morning there&amp;rsquo;s twice as much of it. It always gets more and more.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There&amp;rsquo;s the First Law of Kipple,&amp;rdquo; he said. &amp;ldquo;&amp;lsquo;Kipple drives out nonkipple.&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do Androids Dream of Electric Sheep? by Philip K. Dick&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IT projects are much like the apartments mentioned in Philip K. Dick novel. They tend
to have kipple and, as with apartments, it grows every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve reviewed lots of projects and one of mistakes I often see is about kipple. It looks
minor compared to bugs or architecture mistakes but at the same time it affects both
project and development team significantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So kipple exists. Usually it&amp;rsquo;s cryptic unneeded stuff which one hesitates to delete for
quite vague illogical reasons. Commented out code, files like &lt;code&gt;main.css_old&lt;/code&gt;, unused
methods, five different versions of jQuery, &lt;code&gt;// TODO:&lt;/code&gt; etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s why kipple is both useless and bad:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Broken_windows_theory&#34;&gt;Broken Windows Theory&lt;/a&gt; applies
well to IT projects. If it&amp;rsquo;s allowed not to clean up it&amp;rsquo;s OK to write code which is
of doubtful quality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Often developers comment out big chunks of CSS, JavaScript and HTML which are still
served to end user slowing page loading speed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re actually reading commented out parts of code. It takes time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Large number of unused files may and would confuse newcomers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is unpleasant to work with such kippled project. Feels like code is of a bad quality
even if architecture and code itself is OK.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compile time may be increased.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any version control system remembers everything you&amp;rsquo;ll delete. If there&amp;rsquo;s a need
you can always get it from there. If you fail to remember where it was, tag the commit.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that you may say that it&amp;rsquo;s not important and there&amp;rsquo;s no time for it but I highly
recommend trying it for a few months. You&amp;rsquo;ll see difference in both the project and
overall quality of the code your team produce.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://samdark.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 16:11:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samdark.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m Alex, one of the core maintainers of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.yiiframework.com/&#34;&gt;Yii PHP framework&lt;/a&gt;
for more than 7 years, its representative in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.php-fig.org/&#34;&gt;PHP-FIG&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://slides.rmcreative.ru/&#34;&gt;active conference speaker&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/samdark/&#34;&gt;participant of various other
OpenSource projects&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am &lt;a href=&#34;http://rmcreative.ru/&#34;&gt;blogging in Russian since 2005&lt;/a&gt; and now decided
that it is time to write in English as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;seeking-for-patronage&#34;&gt;Seeking for patronage&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.patreon.com/samdark&#34;&gt;seeking for patronage&lt;/a&gt; in order to work on Yii framework and other OpenSource software.
Would really appreciate if you will support me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding Bug with Binary Search</title>
      <link>https://samdark.github.io/blog/finding-bug-with-binary-search/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 21:52:28 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samdark.github.io/blog/finding-bug-with-binary-search/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Once there&amp;rsquo;s a way to reproduce the issue we need to find code which causes it. Sometimes we&amp;rsquo;re getting totally stuck
for day feeling more and more depressed and, in the end, unable to think clear. Luckily, there&amp;rsquo;s a good way to
find bug even if you have no idea what caused it and even where to set a breakpoint for proper debugging. This way is
binary search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your code is under version control, you&amp;rsquo;re checking out fairly old commit and see if it works. If it works then you&amp;rsquo;re
checking out commit which is in the middle between commit which works and commit which does not and check again. When
there are no commits left in between you get the commit that broke it. If you&amp;rsquo;re using git you&amp;rsquo;re lucky since it has
built-in way to do it via &lt;code&gt;git bisect&lt;/code&gt;. It is quite simple. Let&amp;rsquo;s say you&amp;rsquo;re on current &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; commit and you have
a bug.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;git bisect # starts the process
git bisect bad # current commit has a bug
git bisect good 3.4.5 # I remember that commit tagged 3.4.5 was OK
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that git tells you something like &lt;code&gt;Bisecting: 10 revisions left to test after this&lt;/code&gt; which means
there are about 10 commits between good and bad revision. Also it is checking out a commit which is in
the middle of these ten.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now it&amp;rsquo;s your job to launch the browser or other client and check if the bug is still there. If yes, you&amp;rsquo;re issuing
&lt;code&gt;git bisect bad&lt;/code&gt;. If not &amp;mdash; &lt;code&gt;git bisect good&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;git chooses either left of right part of these 10 commits and repeats again on that part only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few checks you&amp;rsquo;ll get &lt;code&gt;1029012930192390 is first bad commit&lt;/code&gt; message which,
if you answered correctly, indicates exact commit introduced the issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When everything is done you execute &lt;code&gt;git bisect reset&lt;/code&gt; to stop bisecting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alike it could be done with HTML markup of a single page when it&amp;rsquo;s not under version control.
If you have weird bug, delete half of the page HTML and see if issue is still there.
If it is then divide that HTML and check parts again. If it&amp;rsquo;s not then take other half for inspection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pro is that you&amp;rsquo;ll certainly find what caused the bug for sure. Con is that it&amp;rsquo;s not so fast in
case you&amp;rsquo;re not using a tool like git.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Same method could be applied to anything. For example, it&amp;rsquo;s widely used in electronics.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The History of Yii Framework</title>
      <link>https://samdark.github.io/blog/the-history-of-yii-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 21:52:28 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samdark.github.io/blog/the-history-of-yii-framework/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Yii is one of the long-living PHP frameworks out there constantly evolving with time
as PHP is enhanced more and more. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting to know how it was made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;prado&#34;&gt;Prado&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In June 2004 Qiang Xue released first version of PRADO framework. He was inspired
by Apache Tapestry, Borland Delphi and Microsoft ASP.NET.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Roughly at the same time Zend conducted a competition called &amp;ldquo;gophp5&amp;rdquo; to promote
just released PHP 5.0. Qiang re-implemented framework on PHP 5 and won the
competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time project was hosted at SourceForge. In the middle of 2005 Wei Zhuo helped
with i18n and l10n. Prado 2.0 was released.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In May 2005 it was decided to re-write framework again to include new cool features
inspired by Microsoft ASP.NET 2.0. In April 2006 version 3.0 was released. Starting
from it Prado team mostly on code quality and stability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PRADO is still alive and used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;yii&#34;&gt;Yii&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In October 2006 Qiang announced alpha version of Yii at PRADO forums.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;December 3rd 2008 version 1.0.0 was out. Many ideas and some code were taken
from PRADO: ActiveRecord, i18n, l10n etc. More inspiration was from
RoR (convention over configuration, some AR features), symfony1 (filters,
plugins) and Joomla (modules, message translation).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yii 1.0.0 was significantly faster than other frameworks with alike functionality
so community grew fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In January 2010 Yii 1.1 was out. It had form builder, relational queries in AR,
ready to use unit-testing framework and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve joined Yii team in 2010. By the end of the year we were discussing Yii 1.2
while developing version 1.1. In may 2011 it was decided to use newer PHP versions
and fix architectural mistakes i.e. to do 2.0. First commit was made into then
secret repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In May 2013 Yii 2.0 code was presented to public. In October 2014 first stable release
was out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>